Jacob Kenny

New York, NY | 570-716-1763 | <u>jacobkenny05@gmail.com</u> <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Personal Site</u>

WEB ENGINEER

Focused on problem solving to help fast-paced companies achieve results. Utilizes various technologies and stacks to find and deliver clean, innovative solutions. Bilingual in English and Spanish with exceptional client focus and communication. Experienced with Ruby on Rails and Javascript software engineering.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: JavaScript | React | Redux | HTML | CSS | Back End: Ruby | Ruby on Rails | SQL | Git | PostgreSQL

PROJECTS

TripTracker - GitHub | Site | Demo

Exchange rate tracking application that allows users to budget trips to foreign countries

- Utilized Rails API and PostgreSQL to obtain and store exchange rates and user data.
- Automated the process of obtaining real time exchange rate information.

U.S. Game - Github | Site | Demo

Game programmed to reinforce users' knowledge of states' locations and trivia

- Established game logic using React to improve user experience.
- Compiled data in JSON format to use for each state.

Image Scrambler - GitHub | Site | Demo

Tile slide puzzle game

- Defined logic with JavaScript event listeners for the maneuvering of puzzle tiles.
- Established processes for creation of game leaderboard through sorting of completed game objects.

EXPERIENCE

HealthplexNew York, NYCustomer Service Representative02/2021 - Present

- Assisted members by phone by providing information for dental insurance benefits.
- Worked with dentistry offices to determine benefits, dental claim status, and web portal access.

Pennsylvania Treasury

Harrisburg, PA

Customer Service Representative

10/2017 - 11/2019

- Audited submitted forms and legal documentation for completion and accuracy.
- Fielded 40-60 calls per day from customers seeking to maximize their college savings.

DataVerify
Verification of Employment Specialist

Pittsburgh, PA

Verification of Employment Specialist

11/2016 - 07/2017

• Obtained employment verifications from employers on behalf of mortgage lenders

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolNew York, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

New York, NY

12/2019 - 03/2020

Gettysburg CollegeB.A., Spanish; Minor, Educational Studies
Gettysburg, PA
08/2012 - 05/2016